[{
  "course":"Accountant",
  "questionpapers":[{"1-2014":[
    {
      "number": 1,
      "question": "'One caste, One religion and One God for man' was the message of:",
      "options": ["Sree Narayana Guru", "Chattampi Swamikal", "Ayyankali", "Pandit Karuppan"],
      "answer": "Sree Narayana Guru"
    },
    {
      "number": 2,
      "question": "Scientific study of soils is called:",
      "options": ["Cartography", "Pedology", "Physiology", "Palaeology"],
      "answer": "Pedology"
    },
    {
      "number": 3,
      "question": "Father of 'White Revolution':",
      "options": ["M.S. Swaminathan", "Dadabhai Naoroji", "Verghese Kurien", "Amartya Sen"],
      "answer": "Verghese Kurien"
    },
    {
      "number": 4,
      "question": "Who published the famous 'Swadeshabhimani' newspaper?",
      "options": ["Vakkom Moulavi", "C. Krishnan", "E.V. Krishna Pillai", "K.C. Kesava Pillai"],
      "answer": "Vakkom Moulavi"
    },
    {
      "number": 5,
      "question": "First Five Year Plan started in India:",
      "options": ["1950", "1954", "1956", "1951"],
      "answer": "1951"
    },
    {
      "number": 6,
      "question": "Ezuthachan Award Winner of 2013:",
      "options": ["Dr. M. Leelavathi", "Dr. M.K. Sanu", "M.T. Vasudevan Nair", "Attoor Ravivarma"],
      "answer": "M.T. Vasudevan Nair"
    },
    {
      "number": 7,
      "question": "Lines connecting places of equal temperature are called:",
      "options": ["Isobars", "Isohels", "Isonephs", "Isotherms"],
      "answer": "Isotherms"
    },
    {
      "number": 8,
      "question": "Play 'Adukkalayil ninnum arangathekku' was written by:",
      "options": ["E.M.S. Namboothirippad", "K.M. Panikkar", "V.T. Bhattathirippad", "Vishnu Narayanan Namboothiri"],
      "answer": "V.T. Bhattathirippad"
    },
    {
      "number": 9,
      "question": "'Fourth Estate' refers to:",
      "options": ["Press", "Sports", "Judiciary", "Population"],
      "answer": "Press"
    },
    {
      "number": 10,
      "question": "Kaziranga sanctuary is situated in:",
      "options": ["Kerala", "Assam", "Bihar", "Gujarat"],
      "answer": "Assam"
    },
    {
      "number": 11,
      "question": "Mary Kom is associated with:",
      "options": ["Hockey", "Kabaddi", "Football", "Boxing"],
      "answer": "Boxing"
    },
    {
      "number": 12,
      "question": "Leader of 'Ezhava Memorial':",
      "options": ["K. Kelappan", "G.P. Pillai", "Dr. Palpu", "K. Damodharan"],
      "answer": "Dr. Palpu"
    },
    {
      "number": 13,
      "question": "Who launched the Bhoodan Movement?",
      "options": ["Acharya Vinoba Bhave", "C.R. Das", "Motilal Nehru", "Mahatma Gandhi"],
      "answer": "Acharya Vinoba Bhave"
    },
    {
      "number": 14,
      "question": "Bhagat Singh was hanged on:",
      "options": ["23 April 1930", "10 June 1929", "23 March 1931", "13 May 1932"],
      "answer": "23 March 1931"
    },
    {
      "number": 15,
      "question": "'Sahodara Prasthanam' was started by:",
      "options": ["T.K. Madhavan", "C. Sankaran Nair", "Mannathu Padmanabhan", "K. Ayyappan"],
      "answer": "K. Ayyappan"
    },
    {
      "number": 16,
      "question": "Temple Entry Proclamation was issued in the year:",
      "options": ["1921", "1936", "1930", "1932"],
      "answer": "1936"
    },
    {
      "number": 17,
      "question": "Who directed the film 'Indian Rupee'?",
      "options": ["Ranjith", "Blessy", "I.V. Sasi", "Padmarajan"],
      "answer": "Ranjith"
    },
    {
      "number": 18,
      "question": "NASA sent 'Curiosity' to:",
      "options": ["Jupiter", "Venus", "Mars", "Saturn"],
      "answer": "Mars"
    },
    {
      "number": 19,
      "question": "March 8 is observed as:",
      "options": ["Hiroshima Day", "Women's Day", "Population Day", "Teacher's Day"],
      "answer": "Women's Day"
    },
    {
      "number": 20,
      "question": "Which river is not related to the Himalayan rivers?",
      "options": ["River Sindhu", "River Satluj", "River Ganga", "River Cauvery"],
      "answer": "River Cauvery"
    },
    {
      "number": 21,
      "question": "Corporate governance ensures managers look after the interest of:",
      "options": ["Government", "Board of Directors", "Stakeholders", "General Public"],
      "answer": "Stakeholders"
    },
    {
      "number": 22,
      "question": "Outstanding expense is a:",
      "options": ["Personal account", "Real account", "Nominal account", "None of these"],
      "answer": "Nominal account"
    },
    {
      "number": 23,
      "question": "Converting physical share certificates into electronic form is called:",
      "options": ["Rematerialisation", "Dematerialisation", "Gematerialisation", "None of the above"],
      "answer": "Dematerialisation"
    },
    {
      "number": 24,
      "question": "Ratio used to evaluate a firm's ability to meet short-term obligations:",
      "options": ["Solvency ratios", "Profitability ratios", "Liquid ratios", "Activity ratios"],
      "answer": "Liquid ratios"
    },
    {
      "number": 25,
      "question": "Origin of auditing can be traced back to:",
      "options": ["1914", "1494", "1956", "1949"],
      "answer": "1494"
    },
    {
      "number": 26,
      "question": "“Statistics is the science of counting” — whose statement is this?",
      "options": ["Bowley", "Karl Pearson", "Kimbal", "Boddington"],
      "answer": "Boddington"
    },
    {
      "number": 27,
      "question": "Provides accounting information useful to management:",
      "options": ["Financial accounting", "Ledger", "Profit and loss account", "Management accounting"],
      "answer": "Management accounting"
    },
    {
      "number": 28,
      "question": "A budget in capsule form is called:",
      "options": ["Flexible budget", "Master budget", "Sales budget", "Fixed budget"],
      "answer": "Master budget"
    },
    {
      "number": 29,
      "question": "Evidence of a contract of insurance is:",
      "options": ["Policy", "Insurer", "Subject matter", "Premium"],
      "answer": "Policy"
    },
    {
      "number": 30,
      "question": "Hire Purchase Act was enacted in:",
      "options": ["1969", "1970", "1971", "1972"],
      "answer": "1972"
    },
    {
      "number": 31,
      "question": "First Leasing Company of India Ltd was established in:",
      "options": ["Calcutta", "Bombay", "Madras", "Delhi"],
      "answer": "Madras"
    },
    {
      "number": 32,
      "question": "Translating messages into words is called:",
      "options": ["Encoding", "Feedback", "Communication", "Decoding"],
      "answer": "Encoding"
    },
    {
      "number": 33,
      "question": "When shares are forfeited, the share capital account is debited by:",
      "options": ["Paid-up amount", "Called-up amount", "Calls in arrear", "Nominal value of shares"],
      "answer": "Nominal value of shares"
    },
    {
      "number": 34,
      "question": "CII stands for:",
      "options": ["Cost Inflation Index", "Capital Inflation Index", "Cost Interest Index", "Capital Interest Index"],
      "answer": "Cost Inflation Index"
    },
    {
      "number": 35,
      "question": "Concept of marketing mix was developed by:",
      "options": ["Philip Kotler", "W.J. Stanton", "Clark and Clark", "N.H. Borden"],
      "answer": "N.H. Borden"
    },
    {
      "number": 36,
      "question": "Section 89(1) of Income Tax Act deals with relief for:",
      "options": ["Advance salary", "Compensation", "Arrear salary", "Gratuity"],
      "answer": "Arrear salary"
    },
    {
      "number": 37,
      "question": "An agreement to do an impossible act is:",
      "options": ["Voidable", "Void", "Valid", "Illegal"],
      "answer": "Void"
    },
    {
      "number": 38,
      "question": "Registration period of a Trade Mark is:",
      "options": ["5 years", "20 years", "40 years", "10 years"],
      "answer": "10 years"
    },
    {
      "number": 39,
      "question": "Father of Management Process School:",
      "options": ["Henry Fayol", "Elton Mayo", "H.A. Simon", "R.H. Johnson"],
      "answer": "Henry Fayol"
    },
    {
      "number": 40,
      "question": "Central Chief Information Commissioner is appointed by:",
      "options": ["Prime Minister", "Chief Justice of India", "President of India", "Council of Central Ministers"],
      "answer": "President of India"
    },
    {
      "number": 41,
      "question": "Motivation theory X and Y was developed by:",
      "options": ["Herzberg", "M.C. Gregor", "Victor Vroom", "None"],
      "answer": "M.C. Gregor"
    },
    {
      "number": 42,
      "question": "Capital Reduction Account is used in:",
      "options": ["Internal reconstruction", "External reconstruction", "Amalgamation", "Absorption"],
      "answer": "Internal reconstruction"
    },
    {
      "number": 43,
      "question": "Committee on insurance sector reforms in 1993 was headed by:",
      "options": ["P. Chidambaram", "Manmohan Singh", "Narasimham", "R.N. Malhotra"],
      "answer": "R.N. Malhotra"
    },
    {
      "number": 44,
      "question": "To calculate market value using P/E ratio, you need:",
      "options": ["Rate of dividend", "Average profit", "Earnings per share", "Super profits"],
      "answer": "Earnings per share"
    },
    {
      "number": 45,
      "question": "Fund from operations if net profit is ₹50,000, gain on asset sale ₹5,000, depreciation ₹20,000:",
      "options": ["₹70,000", "₹65,000", "₹75,000", "₹55,000"],
      "answer": "₹65,000"
    },
    {
      "number": 46,
      "question": "A bank included in the second schedule of RBI Act is called:",
      "options": ["Scheduled Bank", "Non-Scheduled Bank", "State Co-operative Bank", "Central Co-operative Bank"],
      "answer": "Scheduled Bank"
    },
    {
      "number": 47,
      "question": "Position of imports and exports of a country is called:",
      "options": ["Balance of payments", "Balance of trade", "Terms of trade", "Dumping"],
      "answer": "Balance of payments"
    },
    {
      "number": 48,
      "question": "Electronic transfer of funds is called:",
      "options": ["ECS", "Telebanking", "RTES", "EFT"],
      "answer": "EFT"
    },
    {
      "number": 49,
      "question": "Objectives of companies are given in the:",
      "options": ["Articles of Association", "Prospectus", "Memorandum of Association", "Subsidiary rules"],
      "answer": "Memorandum of Association"
    },
    {
      "number": 50,
      "question": "Depletion method of depreciation is useful for:",
      "options": ["Livestock", "Loose tools", "Mines", "None of these"],
      "answer": "Mines"
    },
    {
      "number": 51,
      "question": "Budget is a:",
      "options": ["Plan of operation", "Statement of probable events", "Collection of historical financial data", "None of these"],
      "answer": "Plan of operation"
    },
    {
      "number": 52,
      "question": "Functional level strategy is also known as:",
      "options": ["Corporate level strategy", "Operating level strategy", "Business level strategy", "All of these"],
      "answer": "Operating level strategy"
    },
    {
      "number": 53,
      "question": "A dollar denominated instrument tradable on stock exchange in Europe:",
      "options": ["FRB", "EDR", "FCCB", "GDR"],
      "answer": "GDR"
    },
    {
      "number": 54,
      "question": "AS-6 relates to:",
      "options": ["Accounting policies", "Valuation of inventories", "Depreciation accounting", "Contingencies"],
      "answer": "Depreciation accounting"
    },
    {
      "number": 55,
      "question": "B Ltd. forfeited 20 shares of ₹10 each, ₹8 called up, for non-payment of first call ₹2. Of these, 15 were reissued at ₹6. Amount transferred to capital reserve is:",
      "options": ["₹60", "₹30", "₹48", "None"],
      "answer": "₹48"
    },
    {
      "number": 56,
      "question": "The insurance effected by an insurance company with another insurance company is called:",
      "options": ["Reinsurance", "Double insurance", "Multiple insurance", "None of these"],
      "answer": "Reinsurance"
    },
    {
      "number": 57,
      "question": "A statutory reserve is a compulsory reserve kept under Banking Regulation Act as per Section:",
      "options": ["9", "15", "18", "17"],
      "answer": "17"
    },
    {
      "number": 58,
      "question": "Offering of ESOS to employees requires:",
      "options": ["Resolution by the board", "Ordinary resolution", "Special resolution in general meeting by shareholders", "Permission from SEBI"],
      "answer": "Special resolution in general meeting by shareholders"
    },
    {
      "number": 59,
      "question": "Statutory report is necessary in the case of:",
      "options": ["Public limited companies", "FERA companies", "Foreign companies", "Private limited companies"],
      "answer": "Public limited companies"
    },
    {
      "number": 60,
      "question": "Preliminary expenses is an example of:",
      "options": ["Current asset", "Tangible asset", "Prepaid expenses", "Fictitious asset"],
      "answer": "Fictitious asset"
    },
    {
      "number": 61,
      "question": "Unrehearsed speech is:",
      "options": ["Impromptu", "Extempore", "Reading from the pre-text", "Memorising"],
      "answer": "Impromptu"
    },
    {
      "number": 62,
      "question": "The first credit rating agency in India is:",
      "options": ["ICRA", "CRISIL", "CARE", "ICSA"],
      "answer": "CRISIL"
    },
    {
      "number": 63,
      "question": "Accounting Standard Board in India was constituted on:",
      "options": ["June 1977", "January 1978", "April 1977", "None of these"],
      "answer": "June 1977"
    },
    {
      "number": 64,
      "question": "Leveraged lease is a special form of leasing developed in recent years in:",
      "options": ["India", "Britain", "Germany", "USA"],
      "answer": "USA"
    },
    {
      "number": 65,
      "question": "Units of finished product not up to the standard and can be rectified are called:",
      "options": ["Defective", "Scrap", "Spoilage", "None"],
      "answer": "Defective"
    },
    {
      "number": 66,
      "question": "The most suitable average for index number is:",
      "options": ["Mean", "Median", "Harmonic mean", "Geometric mean"],
      "answer": "Geometric mean"
    },
    {
      "number": 67,
      "question": "Combination of different securities with varying risk and return is called:",
      "options": ["SAP", "Portfolio", "CAP", "OCP"],
      "answer": "Portfolio"
    },
    {
      "number": 68,
      "question": "Teaming and lading is a method of misappropriation of:",
      "options": ["Goods", "Petty cash", "Cash", "Accounts"],
      "answer": "Cash"
    },
    {
      "number": 69,
      "question": "Misstatements in prospectus by the auditor result in:",
      "options": ["Civil liability", "Criminal liability", "Liability for negligence", "Liability for misfeasance"],
      "answer": "Criminal liability"
    },
    {
      "number": 70,
      "question": "The first general meeting of the company is called:",
      "options": ["Statutory meeting", "Annual general meeting", "Extraordinary meeting", "Emergency meeting"],
      "answer": "Statutory meeting"
    },
    {
      "number": 71,
      "question": "Operating system is a:",
      "options": ["System software", "Application software", "Hardware", "Firmware"],
      "answer": "System software"
    },
    {
      "number": 72,
      "question": "Binary number system has the base:",
      "options": ["10", "1", "2", "16"],
      "answer": "2"
    },
    {
      "number": 73,
      "question": "Nibble is a group of:",
      "options": ["4 bits", "6 bits", "8 bits", "16 bits"],
      "answer": "4 bits"
    },
    {
      "number": 74,
      "question": "UNIX is a:",
      "options": ["Programming language", "Compiler", "Operating system", "File system"],
      "answer": "Operating system"
    },
    {
      "number": 75,
      "question": "In a hard disk, each track is a collection of:",
      "options": ["Cylinders", "Disks", "Files", "Sectors"],
      "answer": "Sectors"
    },
    {
      "number": 76,
      "question": "Which of the following is not an input device?",
      "options": ["Microphone", "Stylus", "Speaker", "Joystick"],
      "answer": "Speaker"
    },
    {
      "number": 77,
      "question": "Which of the following is not true about ROM?",
      "options": ["Firmware", "Volatile", "Read only", "None of these"],
      "answer": "Volatile"
    },
    {
      "number": 78,
      "question": "NTFS is:",
      "options": ["Network switch", "Router", "Operating system", "File system"],
      "answer": "File system"
    },
    {
      "number": 79,
      "question": "Which of the following is not a web browser?",
      "options": ["Internet Explorer", "Mozilla Firefox", "Opera", "Apache"],
      "answer": "Apache"
    },
    {
      "number": 80,
      "question": "Graphic representation of program logic sequence is known as:",
      "options": ["Icons", "Algorithm", "Flow chart", "Pseudo code"],
      "answer": "Flow chart"
    },
    {
      "number": 81,
      "question": "An installation file usually has the following extension:",
      "options": [".org", ".doc", ".zip", ".exe"],
      "answer": ".exe"
    },
    {
      "number": 82,
      "question": "Bluetooth is a:",
      "options": ["Wireless network", "Antivirus", "Wired LAN", "Type of mobile phone"],
      "answer": "Wireless network"
    },
    {
      "number": 83,
      "question": "Which of the following is not an Internet access method?",
      "options": ["DSL", "Dial-up", "Podcast", "Cable"],
      "answer": "Podcast"
    },
    {
      "number": 84,
      "question": "1 GB is:",
      "options": ["1024 bits", "1024 bytes", "1024 KB", "1024 MB"],
      "answer": "1024 MB"
    },
    {
      "number": 85,
      "question": "Which of the following is not an example of a search engine?",
      "options": ["Google", "Facebook", "Yahoo", "AltaVista"],
      "answer": "Facebook"
    },
    {
      "number": 86,
      "question": "Which of the following is not a monitor type?",
      "options": ["CRT", "LCD", "LED", "Blu-ray"],
      "answer": "Blu-ray"
    },
    {
      "number": 87,
      "question": "The BIOS is responsible for handling:",
      "options": ["Memory", "Input-output operations", "File management", "Directory management"],
      "answer": "Input-output operations"
    },
    {
      "number": 88,
      "question": "A small text file that some websites automatically store on your hard drive when you visit the site is called:",
      "options": ["Spam", "Blog", "Cookie", "Worm"],
      "answer": "Cookie"
    },
    {
      "number": 89,
      "question": "GIF is a file format usually associated with:",
      "options": ["Documents", "Spreadsheets", "Images", "Compressed files"],
      "answer": "Images"
    },
    {
      "number": 90,
      "question": "In programming, syntax error is:",
      "options": ["Violation of programming language rules", "Use of incorrect sequence of statements", "Due to lack of free memory space", "Logical mistake in the program"],
      "answer": "Violation of programming language rules"
    },
    {
      "number": 91,
      "question": "When a program's address space can be greater than its actual real memory, the system is said to implement:",
      "options": ["Cache memory", "Virtual memory", "Secondary memory", "File management"],
      "answer": "Virtual memory"
    },
    {
      "number": 92,
      "question": "Compiler is used to translate:",
      "options": ["Machine language into high-level language", "Assembly language into high-level language", "High-level language into machine language", "High-level language into assembly language"],
      "answer": "High-level language into machine language"
    },
    {
      "number": 93,
      "question": "Trojan horse is a:",
      "options": ["Search engine", "Operating system", "Programming language", "Malicious software"],
      "answer": "Malicious software"
    },
    {
      "number": 94,
      "question": "Broadcasting of audio or video content over the Internet is known as:",
      "options": ["Wiki", "Webcast", "Blog", "Instant messaging"],
      "answer": "Webcast"
    },
    {
      "number": 95,
      "question": "Microsoft Excel is a software for:",
      "options": ["Word processing", "Spreadsheet", "Database", "Presentation"],
      "answer": "Spreadsheet"
    },
    {
      "number": 96,
      "question": "Bootstrap loader is a program normally stored in:",
      "options": ["ROM", "RAM", "Hard disk", "Cache memory"],
      "answer": "ROM"
    },
    {
      "number": 97,
      "question": "Firewalls are used for:",
      "options": ["Cyber security", "E-commerce", "E-mail", "Wireless networks"],
      "answer": "Cyber security"
    },
    {
      "number": 98,
      "question": "An example of impact type printer is:",
      "options": ["Dot matrix", "Inkjet", "Laser", "All of these"],
      "answer": "Dot matrix"
    },
    {
      "number": 99,
      "question": "The IEEE standard for wireless LAN is:",
      "options": ["802.2", "802.11", "802.3", "802.13"],
      "answer": "802.11"
    },
    {
      "number": 100,
      "question": "In Database Management System, the overall design of the database is called:",
      "options": ["Entity", "Schema", "Data manager", "DML"],
      "answer": "Schema"
    }
                  ]},{"2-2014":[
  {
    "number": 1,
    "question": "The continuous process of measuring a firm's goods, practices and services against those of its toughest competitors is:",
    "options": ["Megamarketing", "Overmarketing", "Benchmarketing", "None of these"],
    "answer": "Benchmarketing"
  },
  {
    "number": 2,
    "question": "Performance appraisal done by supervisors, peers, subordinates, employees themselves, users of services and consultants is known as:",
    "options": ["360° Performance Appraisal", "Forced Choice Method", "BARS", "Group Appraisal"],
    "answer": "360° Performance Appraisal"
  },
  {
    "number": 3,
    "question": "Which committee reviewed the role, structure and operations of development financial institutions and banks in 1998?",
    "options": ["Verma Committee", "Narasimham Committee", "Khan Committee", "None of these"],
    "answer": "Khan Committee"
  },
  {
    "number": 4,
    "question": "An agreement in restraint of marriage is valid in the case of:",
    "options": ["Minor", "Uneducated", "Married", "None of these"],
    "answer": "Minor"
  },
  {
    "number": 5,
    "question": "An investor must be very cautious when buying a share that belongs to:",
    "options": ["A Group", "S Group", "Z Group", "None of these"],
    "answer": "Z Group"
  },
  {
    "number": 6,
    "question": "In which production function is the degree of homogeneity always 1?",
    "options": ["Cobb-Douglas Production Function", "Homogeneous Production Function", "Linear Homogeneous Production Function", "None of these"],
    "answer": "Linear Homogeneous Production Function"
  },
  {
    "number": 7,
    "question": "Which of the following ratio is not used for determining the solvency of a concern?",
    "options": ["Debt-Equity Ratio", "Proprietory Ratio", "Debt Service Ratio", "Creditors Turnover Ratio"],
    "answer": "Creditors Turnover Ratio"
  },
  {
    "number": 8,
    "question": "Rent of owned building is:",
    "options": ["Sunk Cost", "Shut Down Cost", "Imputed Cost", "Out of Pocket Cost"],
    "answer": "Imputed Cost"
  },
  {
    "number": 9,
    "question": "Matrix type of marketing organisation is most suited for:",
    "options": ["Single Product, Single Market Situation", "Multi Product, Single Market Situation", "Multi Product, Multi Market Situation", "Single Product, Multi Market Situation"],
    "answer": "Multi Product, Multi Market Situation"
  },
  {
    "number": 10,
    "question": "Franco price covers:",
    "options": ["Charges for placing goods near the ship", "Cost of loading goods on board", "Cost, Freight and Insurance", "All charges necessary for sending goods to buyer’s place"],
    "answer": "All charges necessary for sending goods to buyer’s place"
  },
  {
    "number": 11,
    "question": "Which of the following is not an important source of power of a leader in an organisation?",
    "options": ["Referent Power", "Behavioural Power", "Legitimate Power", "Coercive Power"],
    "answer": "Behavioural Power"
  },
  {
    "number": 12,
    "question": "Which bank set up its merchant banking division in 1969 for the first time in India?",
    "options": ["State Bank of India", "Grindlays Bank", "ICICI", "None of these"],
    "answer": "Grindlays Bank"
  },
  {
    "number": 13,
    "question": "Novation means:",
    "options": ["Cancellation of the existing contract", "Change in one or more terms", "Substitution of existing contract for a new one", "None of these"],
    "answer": "Substitution of existing contract for a new one"
  },
  {
    "number": 14,
    "question": "Which is a tradable instrument with detachable warrant for equity shares after a fixed period?",
    "options": ["Secured Premium Notes", "Zero Coupon Bond", "Collable Bond", "Equity Warrant"],
    "answer": "Secured Premium Notes"
  },
  {
    "number": 15,
    "question": "Which of the following is not a property of isoquant?",
    "options": ["Downward Sloping", "Convex", "Negative Slope", "Positive Slope"],
    "answer": "Positive Slope"
  },
  {
    "number": 16,
    "question": "Which of the following is a non-current liability?",
    "options": ["Mortgage Loan", "Bank Balance", "Outstanding Salary", "Salary"],
    "answer": "Mortgage Loan"
  },
  {
    "number": 17,
    "question": "Which method is used in the control of spare parts?",
    "options": ["ABC Analysis", "HML Analysis", "JIT", "VED Analysis"],
    "answer": "ABC Analysis"
  },
  {
    "number": 18,
    "question": "The aspect of marketing that discourages customers temporarily or permanently is:",
    "options": ["Remarketing", "Demarketing", "Overmarketing", "None of these"],
    "answer": "Demarketing"
  },
  {
    "number": 19,
    "question": "A statement of minimum acceptable human qualities for a job is:",
    "options": ["Job Specification", "Job Description", "Job Classification", "Job Enrichment"],
    "answer": "Job Specification"
  },
  {
    "number": 20,
    "question": "Expansion and contraction of currency takes place through the ______ of RBI.",
    "options": ["Banking Department", "Currency Department", "Credit Department", "None of these"],
    "answer": "Currency Department"
  },
  {
    "number": 21,
    "question": "Rejecting a true null hypothesis is committing a:",
    "options": ["Type I Error", "Type II Error", "Type III Error", "Sampling Error"],
    "answer": "Type I Error"
  },
  {
    "number": 22,
    "question": "An agreement to pay based on whether it rains is a:",
    "options": ["Quasi Contract", "Contingent Contract", "Wagering Agreement", "Voidable Contract"],
    "answer": "Wagering Agreement"
  },
  {
    "number": 23,
    "question": "A company making a public issue through book building process issues:",
    "options": ["Shelf Prospectus", "Statement in Lieu of Prospectus", "Deemed Prospectus", "Red-Herring Prospectus"],
    "answer": "Red-Herring Prospectus"
  },
  {
    "number": 24,
    "question": "Grey market is an:",
    "options": ["Official Market", "Unofficial Market", "Regulated Market", "None of these"],
    "answer": "Unofficial Market"
  },
  {
    "number": 25,
    "question": "Price discrimination is possible in:",
    "options": ["Perfect Competition", "Monopoly", "Monopolistic Competition", "None of these"],
    "answer": "Monopoly"
  },
  {
    "number": 26,
    "question": "If an asset transferred without consideration is again transferred by the transferee, the resultant gain or loss is clubbed with the income of:",
    "options": ["Former transferor", "Former transferee", "Latter transferee", "None of these"],
    "answer": "Former transferor"
  },
  {
    "number": 27,
    "question": "______ is calculated to find the extent to which earnings per share have been retained in the business.",
    "options": ["Dividend pay-out ratio", "Dividend yield ratio", "Price earning ratio", "None of these"],
    "answer": "Dividend pay-out ratio"
  },
  {
    "number": 28,
    "question": "If the annual usage is 6000 units, cost of placing an order is Rs.60 and annual carrying cost per unit is Rs.2, EOQ is:",
    "options": ["60 unit", "600 unit", "6000 unit", "300 unit"],
    "answer": "600 unit"
  },
  {
    "number": 29,
    "question": "Sales based on verbal understanding between buyers and sellers without mentioning the rate with the understanding that buyer will pay the prevailing rate is:",
    "options": ["Sale by open auction", "Dara sale", "Moghum sale", "None of these"],
    "answer": "Moghum sale"
  },
  {
    "number": 30,
    "question": "Market integration is the strategy of:",
    "options": ["Counter integration", "Additional segmentation", "Product differentiation", "Concentrated marketing"],
    "answer": "Concentrated marketing"
  },
  {
    "number": 31,
    "question": "What is the significance of the year “1926” in the development of HRM in India?",
    "options": ["The Payment of Wages Act was passed", "The All India Trade Union Congress was formed", "Indian Trade Unions Act was passed", "The Bombay Trade Disputes Conciliation Act was passed"],
    "answer": "The All India Trade Union Congress was formed"
  },
  {
    "number": 32,
    "question": "______ was established in 1990 with an objective to provide an alternate market for the securities of smaller companies.",
    "options": ["OTCEI", "NSE", "BOLT", "SHCIL"],
    "answer": "OTCEI"
  },
  {
    "number": 33,
    "question": "If the variables are measured on nominal and ordinal scales, the tools of analysis are called ______ statistics.",
    "options": ["Parametric", "Non-parametric", "Descriptive", "Inferential"],
    "answer": "Non-parametric"
  },
  {
    "number": 34,
    "question": "A stipulation in a contract of sale of goods whose violation by seller gives a right of rescission to buyer is called:",
    "options": ["Guarantee", "Warranty", "Condition", "Term"],
    "answer": "Condition"
  },
  {
    "number": 35,
    "question": "Which of the following is not a mutual fund scheme?",
    "options": ["Equity schemes", "Debt schemes", "Balanced schemes", "Mutual benefit schemes"],
    "answer": "Mutual benefit schemes"
  },
  {
    "number": 36,
    "question": "Variables that contain data with only two categories are called ______ variables.",
    "options": ["Interval", "Ordinal", "Nominal", "Dichotomous"],
    "answer": "Dichotomous"
  },
  {
    "number": 37,
    "question": "The income elasticity of demand is negative for a:",
    "options": ["Positive good", "Normal good", "Elastic good", "Inferior good"],
    "answer": "Inferior good"
  },
  {
    "number": 38,
    "question": "In the case of gift of movable property, tax is levied on the basis of:",
    "options": ["Fair market value", "Stamp duty value", "Declared value", "None of these"],
    "answer": "Fair market value"
  },
  {
    "number": 39,
    "question": "The term “Caveat Emptor” means:",
    "options": ["Let the seller beware", "Let the buyer beware", "Let the buyer and seller beware", "None of these"],
    "answer": "Let the buyer beware"
  },
  {
    "number": 40,
    "question": "Rapid penetration strategy opted in the introduction stage of Product Life Cycle is:",
    "options": ["High price, high promotion", "High price, low promotion", "Low price, high promotion", "Low price, low promotion"],
    "answer": "Low price, high promotion"
  },
  {
    "number": 41,
    "question": "______ means shares having no face value.",
    "options": ["Sweat equity", "Deferred shares", "Equity shares", "No par stock"],
    "answer": "No par stock"
  },
  {
    "number": 42,
    "question": "If there is no accessible sampling frame, ______ sampling is used.",
    "options": ["Judgement", "Snowball", "Systematic", "Random"],
    "answer": "Snowball"
  },
  {
    "number": 43,
    "question": "The threat to commit suicide amounts to:",
    "options": ["Undue influence", "Misrepresentation", "Coercion", "Fraud"],
    "answer": "Coercion"
  },
  {
    "number": 44,
    "question": "The principle that a company cannot lawfully do that which is beyond its powers is explained by:",
    "options": ["Doctrine of ultra vires", "Doctrine of indoor management", "Doctrine of constructive notice", "None of these"],
    "answer": "Doctrine of ultra vires"
  },
  {
    "number": 45,
    "question": "“A rupee tomorrow is worth less than a rupee today” relates to:",
    "options": ["Discounting principle", "Opportunity cost principle", "Equi-marginal principle", "None of these"],
    "answer": "Discounting principle"
  },
  {
    "number": 46,
    "question": "Where the employee pays rent which is less than 10% of salary, HRA is:",
    "options": ["Not taxable", "Partly taxable", "Fully taxable", "Proportionally taxable"],
    "answer": "Fully taxable"
  },
  {
    "number": 47,
    "question": "______ scheme is more beneficial to the workers at lower levels of efficiency:",
    "options": ["Rowan", "Halsey", "Halsey-Weir", "None of these"],
    "answer": "Rowan"
  },
  {
    "number": 48,
    "question": "Who has introduced the concept of marketing-mix?",
    "options": ["N.H. Bordon", "E.F.L. Brech", "Henry L. Hernam", "William J. Stanton"],
    "answer": "N.H. Bordon"
  },
  {
    "number": 49,
    "question": "Which of the following is not promotional pricing?",
    "options": ["Special event pricing", "Price leaders", "Superficial discounting", "Prestige pricing"],
    "answer": "Prestige pricing"
  },
  {
    "number": 50,
    "question": "______ is a process of fixing price for an issue of securities on a feedback from potential investors based on their perception about a company:",
    "options": ["Tender method", "Book building", "Underwritten placement", "None of these"],
    "answer": "Book building"
  },
  {
    "number": 51,
    "question": "______ samples are best suited for exploratory research.",
    "options": ["Systematic", "Convenience", "Judgement", "Random"],
    "answer": "Convenience"
  },
  {
    "number": 52,
    "question": "Which of the following is not a form of delivery of goods?",
    "options": ["Constructive delivery", "Structured delivery", "Actual delivery", "Symbolic delivery"],
    "answer": "Structured delivery"
  },
  {
    "number": 53,
    "question": "The transfer of right shares in favour of a third party is called:",
    "options": ["Renouncement of shares", "Allotment of shares", "Transfer of shares", "Transmission of shares"],
    "answer": "Renouncement of shares"
  },
  {
    "number": 54,
    "question": "Take out financing is:",
    "options": ["A sort of bank financing", "Coming under hire purchase", "Coming under lease financing", "None of these"],
    "answer": "A sort of bank financing"
  },
  {
    "number": 55,
    "question": "Capital gains used for acquiring land, buildings, plant or machinery to shift the industrial undertaking to non-urban area is eligible for exemption under section ______ of I.T. Act.",
    "options": ["54A", "54B", "54GA", "54G"],
    "answer": "54GA"
  },
  {
    "number": 56,
    "question": "Retention money is the difference between the work certified and:",
    "options": ["Work uncertified", "Contract price", "Cash received", "None of these"],
    "answer": "Cash received"
  },
  {
    "number": 57,
    "question": "In the intensive growth strategies, develop new markets for its current products is:",
    "options": ["Market penetration strategy", "Market development strategy", "Product development strategy", "None of these"],
    "answer": "Market development strategy"
  },
  {
    "number": 58,
    "question": "The authority to implement Ecomark scheme on voluntary basis in India is:",
    "options": ["The Central Pollution Control Board", "Environment and Pollution Board", "Eco-planning Management Board", "None of these"],
    "answer": "The Central Pollution Control Board"
  },
  {
    "number": 59,
    "question": "Contago charge is related to:",
    "options": ["Liquidation by payment of differences", "Liquidation in full", "Carry over to next settlement", "None of these"],
    "answer": "Carry over to next settlement"
  },
  {
    "number": 60,
    "question": "______ scale is also called summated rating scale.",
    "options": ["Likert", "Semantic differential", "Nominal", "Ordinal"],
    "answer": "Likert"
  },
  {
    "number": 61,
    "question": "Which of the following is not representing a virtual organisation?",
    "options": ["Digital organisation", "Network organisation", "Modular organisation", "Concurrent organisation"],
    "answer": "Concurrent organisation"
  },
  {
    "number": 62,
    "question": "Dow theory is associated with:",
    "options": ["Market analysis", "Technical analysis", "Fundamental analysis", "All of these"],
    "answer": "All of these"
  },
  {
    "number": 63,
    "question": "Income tax is shared among Centre and States based on the recommendations of:",
    "options": ["Finance ministry", "Finance commission", "Planning commission", "None of these"],
    "answer": "Finance commission"
  },
  {
    "number": 64,
    "question": "Supervisor's salary is an example of:",
    "options": ["Variable cost", "Fixed cost", "Step cost", "Semi-variable cost"],
    "answer": "Fixed cost"
  },
  {
    "number": 65,
    "question": "Market orchestration is the technique of selecting:",
    "options": ["Product integration", "Additional segmentation", "Concentrated marketing", "Marketing mix"],
    "answer": "Marketing mix"
  },
  {
    "number": 66,
    "question": "Settlement of Forward Delivery contract cannot be done through:",
    "options": ["Liquidation in full", "Liquidation by payment of difference", "Carry over to the next settlement", "None of these"],
    "answer": "None of these"
  },
  {
    "number": 67,
    "question": "The listing of the accessible population from which the sample is drawn is called:",
    "options": ["Sample design", "Sample block", "Sampling frame", "Sampling premises"],
    "answer": "Sampling frame"
  },
  {
    "number": 68,
    "question": "Long-term capital losses can be set-off against:",
    "options": ["Any capital gain", "Long-term capital gains only", "Short-term capital gains only", "None of these"],
    "answer": "Long-term capital gains only"
  },
  {
    "number": 69,
    "question": "For the purpose of verification, material cost variance is equal to:",
    "options": ["Material price variance + material usage variance", "Material price variance + material yield variance", "Material mix variance + material yield variance", "Material usage variance + material mix variance"],
    "answer": "Material price variance + material usage variance"
  },
  {
    "number": 70,
    "question": "When the buyers have too narrow an image of the brand, it is known as:",
    "options": ["Under positioning error", "Confused positioning error", "Doubtful positioning error", "Overpositioning error"],
    "answer": "Overpositioning error"
  },
  {
    "number": 71,
    "question": "A name neither related to product, nor the producer is termed as:",
    "options": ["Coined name", "Arbitrary name", "Suggestive name", "None of these"],
    "answer": "Arbitrary name"
  },
  {
    "number": 72,
    "question": "Consumers likely to retain only that information which support their beliefs and attitudes are known as:",
    "options": ["Selective exposure", "Selective distortion", "Selective retention", "None of the above"],
    "answer": "Selective retention"
  },
  {
    "number": 73,
    "question": "______ was set up by RBI in 1994 for developing secondary market for Government dated securities.",
    "options": ["SHCIL", "OTCEI", "NSE", "STCI"],
    "answer": "STCI"
  },
  {
    "number": 74,
    "question": "Coefficient of variation is developed by:",
    "options": ["Rensis Likert", "Wilkoxen", "Pearson", "R.A.Fisher"],
    "answer": "R.A.Fisher"
  },
  {
    "number": 75,
    "question": "The concept of \"producer company\" is based on the recommendations of committee led by:",
    "options": ["Narayana Murthy", "Y.B. Tandon", "P.K. Gupta", "Y.K. Alagh"],
    "answer": "Y.K. Alagh"
  },
  {
    "number": 76,
    "question": "Venture capital Financing is:",
    "options": ["High risk low return business", "High risk high return business", "Low risk high return business", "None of these"],
    "answer": "High risk high return business"
  },
  {
    "number": 77,
    "question": "Products which do not give immediate satisfaction to customers, but these are beneficial in the long-run are:",
    "options": ["Pleasing products", "Satutory products", "Desirable products", "Deficient products"],
    "answer": "Desirable products"
  },
  {
    "number": 78,
    "question": "A projector that can project objects on to a screen at rates so fast that the viewer cannot detect the message is:",
    "options": ["Psychogalvanometer", "Eye camera", "Techistoscope", "None of these"],
    "answer": "Techistoscope"
  },
  {
    "number": 79,
    "question": "Under the \"Family Decision Making\" model of consumer behaviour those family members who control the flow of information about a product/service are called:",
    "options": ["Influencer", "Dealers", "Buyers", "Gatekeepers"],
    "answer": "Gatekeepers"
  },
  {
    "number": 80,
    "question": "White candlestick represents:",
    "options": ["Beerish trend", "Neutral trend", "Bullish trend", "None of these"],
    "answer": "Bullish trend"
  },
  {
    "number": 81,
    "question": "The Keibul Lamjao National park, an integral part of Loktak lake, world's only floating National Park, is located in the state of:",
    "options": ["Himachal Pradesh", "Manipur", "Uttarakhand", "West Bengal"],
    "answer": "Manipur"
  },
  {
    "number": 82,
    "question": "Adam's bridge connects:",
    "options": ["India and Myanmar", "India and Pakistan", "India and Srilanka", "India and China"],
    "answer": "India and Srilanka"
  },
  {
    "number": 83,
    "question": "Which of the following is known as a universal fibre?",
    "options": ["Cotton", "Silk", "Linen", "Wool"],
    "answer": "Cotton"
  },
  {
    "number": 84,
    "question": "The Salt Satyagraha began with the Dandi March on:",
    "options": ["12th March 1930", "12th April 1930", "12th May 1930", "12th June 1930"],
    "answer": "12th March 1930"
  },
  {
    "number": 85,
    "question": "Central statistical organisation is located in:",
    "options": ["Mumbai", "Bangalore", "Delhi", "Kolkata"],
    "answer": "Delhi"
  },
  {
    "number": 86,
    "question": "Mars Orbiter Mission (Mangalyan) was launched on 5 November 2013 using the space vehicle:",
    "options": ["PSLV-CA-9", "PSLV-C-25", "PSVL-XL-22", "PSLV-20"],
    "answer": "PSLV-C-25"
  },
  {
    "number": 87,
    "question": "Prime Minister of India inaugurated Sardar Vallabhai Patel national museum on 29 October 2013:",
    "options": ["New Delhi", "Kolkata", "Guwahati", "Ahmedabad"],
    "answer": "Ahmedabad"
  },
  {
    "number": 88,
    "question": "Sachin Tendulkar, the cricket icon of India, bid farewell to cricket matches after the final test against:",
    "options": ["Australia", "West Indies", "Newzealand", "England"],
    "answer": "West Indies"
  },
  {
    "number": 89,
    "question": "The Bollywood actress who was honoured in the house of commons in London in October 2013:",
    "options": ["Priyanka Chopra", "Aishwarya Rai", "Kareena Kapoor", "Deepika Padukone"],
    "answer": "Aishwarya Rai"
  },
  {
    "number": 90,
    "question": "The autobiography \"Kathayillathavante katha\" which got Kendra Sahithya academy award was written by:",
    "options": ["Attoor Ravivarma", "Sachidanandan", "P. Ramachandran", "M.N. Palooru"],
    "answer": "M.N. Palooru"
  },
  {
    "number": 91,
    "question": "Kasturirangan panel recommended a ban on developmental activities in ecologically sensitive area spread over six states of India. Which of the following states does not come under the reference of Kasturirangan panel report?",
    "options": ["Karnataka", "Goa", "Maharashtra", "Andra Pradesh"],
    "answer": "Andra Pradesh"
  },
  {
    "number": 92,
    "question": "Kerala coast was affected by the Indian ocean Tsunami for the first time in:",
    "options": ["2000", "2003", "2004", "2005"],
    "answer": "2004"
  },
  {
    "number": 93,
    "question": "Bekal fort of Kasargod in Kerala was constructed by:",
    "options": ["Shivappa Nayak", "Tipu Sultan", "Bhaskara Ravi II", "Ikkeri Nayak"],
    "answer": "Shivappa Nayak"
  },
  {
    "number": 94,
    "question": "Which of the following is an east flowing river in Kerala?",
    "options": ["Pamba", "Chaliyar", "Pambar", "Chandragiri"],
    "answer": "Pambar"
  },
  {
    "number": 95,
    "question": "Attappadi reserve forest is in the district of:",
    "options": ["Wayanad", "Idukki", "Thrissur", "Palakkad"],
    "answer": "Palakkad"
  },
  {
    "number": 96,
    "question": "Which of the following renaissance leader is referred to as Sampooranathevan?",
    "options": ["Thycaud Ayya", "Ayya Vaikundar", "Kumara Guru", "Chattampi Swami"],
    "answer": "Ayya Vaikundar"
  },
  {
    "number": 97,
    "question": "Velutheri Kesavan Vaidhyan was one of the disciples of:",
    "options": ["Sree Narayana Guru", "Chattampi Swami", "Thycaud Ayya", "Brahmananda Sivayogi"],
    "answer": "Chattampi Swami"
  },
  {
    "number": 98,
    "question": "Who among the following was a leader of Vaikom Satyagraha?",
    "options": ["T. K. Madhavan", "A.K. Gopalan", "Barrister G.P. Pillai", "C. Kesavan"],
    "answer": "T. K. Madhavan"
  },
  {
    "number": 99,
    "question": "\"Vedadhikara Niroopanam\" was written by:",
    "options": ["Sree Narayana Guru", "Kumara Guru", "Chattampi Swami", "Pandit Karuppan"],
    "answer": "Chattampi Swami"
  },
  {
    "number": 100,
    "question": "'Malayalee memorial' was submitted before:",
    "options": ["Swathy Thirunal", "Rani Gouri Lakshmi Bhai", "Ayilyam Thirunal", "Sree Moolam Thirunal"],
    "answer": "Ayilyam Thirunal"
  }
                  ]},{"3-2014":[
  {
    "number": 1,
    "question": "Holy Hell : A Memoir of Faith, Devotion and Pure Madness is a book written by:",
    "options": ["James P. Farwell", "Jennifer Lawrence", "Gail Tredwell", "Leonardo Di Caprio"],
    "answer": "Gail Tredwell"
  },
  {
    "number": 2,
    "question": "Who has been named PETA Person of the Year?",
    "options": ["Shashi Tharoor", "Hery Rajaonarimampiania", "Ghulam Nabi Azad", "Ban Ki-Moon"],
    "answer": "Shashi Tharoor"
  },
  {
    "number": 3,
    "question": "Sree Narayana Guru died in the year:",
    "options": ["1922", "1924", "1926", "1928"],
    "answer": "1928"
  },
  {
    "number": 4,
    "question": "The British plan to imprison Gandhiji before 'Quit India' movement was called:",
    "options": ["Operation White Point", "Operation Zero Hour", "Operation Success Night", "Operation Defend Star"],
    "answer": "Operation Zero Hour"
  },
  {
    "number": 5,
    "question": "Champion of Australian Open Women's Singles 2014:",
    "options": ["Dominika Cibulkova", "Li Na", "Victoria Azarenka", "Kim Clijster"],
    "answer": "Li Na"
  },
  {
    "number": 6,
    "question": "Indian leader dismissed from Indian Civil Service:",
    "options": ["Tej Bahadur Sapru", "Subhash Chandra Bose", "Surendranath Banerji", "Dadabhai Naoroji"],
    "answer": "Surendranath Banerji"
  },
  {
    "number": 7,
    "question": "Watershed between India and Myanmar is formed by:",
    "options": ["Naga Hills", "Kanchanjunga", "Aravallis", "Shivalic Hills"],
    "answer": "Naga Hills"
  },
  {
    "number": 8,
    "question": "First woman head of State Bank of India:",
    "options": ["Kanika Bhutani Anand", "Begum Parveen Sultana", "Kirti Garg", "Arundhati Bhattacharya"],
    "answer": "Arundhati Bhattacharya"
  },
  {
    "number": 9,
    "question": "River 'Churni' in Arthasastra refers to:",
    "options": ["Narmada", "Periyar", "Kaveri", "Bharatapuzha"],
    "answer": "Bharatapuzha"
  },
  {
    "number": 10,
    "question": "India's representative at 22nd Commonwealth Heads meet in Colombo:",
    "options": ["Manmohan Singh", "A.K. Antony", "Salman Khurshid", "Shashi Tharoor"],
    "answer": "Salman Khurshid"
  },
  {
    "number": 11,
    "question": "First moon rover mission of China:",
    "options": ["Chang'e-3", "Shenzhou-10", "Tiangong-1", "Long March-2-F"],
    "answer": "Chang'e-3"
  },
  {
    "number": 12,
    "question": "Bandar Seri Begawan is the capital of:",
    "options": ["Kiribati", "Micronesia", "Papua New Guinea", "Brunei"],
    "answer": "Brunei"
  },
  {
    "number": 13,
    "question": "Country that withdrew from Commonwealth calling it neo-colonist:",
    "options": ["South Africa", "Gambia", "Sudan", "DR Congo"],
    "answer": "Gambia"
  },
  {
    "number": 14,
    "question": "Birthplace of Ayyankali:",
    "options": ["Amboori", "Kaniyapuram", "Venganur", "Neyyattinkara"],
    "answer": "Venganur"
  },
  {
    "number": 15,
    "question": "Indian PM who attended first UN environment conference:",
    "options": ["Jawaharlal Nehru", "Lal Bahadur Sastri", "Indira Gandhi", "Rajeev Gandhi"],
    "answer": "Indira Gandhi"
  },
  {
    "number": 16,
    "question": "UNESCO declared Nicobar Islands as:",
    "options": ["World Biosphere Reserve", "World Heritage Site", "Environment Friendly Site", "Historical Site"],
    "answer": "World Biosphere Reserve"
  },
  {
    "number": 17,
    "question": "Arakan Yoma is extension of Himalayas in:",
    "options": ["Nepal", "India", "Bhutan", "Myanmar"],
    "answer": "Myanmar"
  },
  {
    "number": 18,
    "question": "Author of book titled '1283':",
    "options": ["Sania Mirza", "Pele", "Rafael Nadal", "Maradona"],
    "answer": "Rafael Nadal"
  },
  {
    "number": 19,
    "question": "Founder of magazine 'The Indian Sociologist':",
    "options": ["Subhash Chandra Bose", "Aurobindo Ghosh", "Surya Sen", "Shyamji Krishna Varma"],
    "answer": "Shyamji Krishna Varma"
  },
  {
    "number": 20,
    "question": "Aitchson's remark “could not play off Mohammadans…” relates to:",
    "options": ["Revolt of 1857", "Non-Cooperation Movement", "Civil Disobedience Movement", "Quit India Movement"],
    "answer": "Revolt of 1857"
  },
  {
    "number": 21,
    "question": "A ring road ___ around the city.",
    "options": ["is building", "have been building", "is being built", "has built"],
    "answer": "is being built"
  },
  {
    "number": 22,
    "question": "It is high time you ___ that you are not the most important person.",
    "options": ["have been realized", "realized", "realizing", "realize"],
    "answer": "realized"
  },
  {
    "number": 23,
    "question": "He is one of the best actors that ___ ever lived.",
    "options": ["has", "has been", "have been", "have"],
    "answer": "have been"
  },
  {
    "number": 24,
    "question": "Indirect speech of “Let the guards be armed,” he ordered:",
    "options": ["The guards ordered him to be armed.", "He ordered that the guards should be armed.", "He suggested that let the guards were armed.", "He suggested the guards that they are armed."],
    "answer": "He ordered that the guards should be armed."
  },
  {
    "number": 25,
    "question": "Choose the correct sentence:",
    "options": ["Ancient India was largely indebted to Iranian ideas and practices.", "...by Iranian ideas...", "...with Iranian ideas...", "...in Iranian ideas..."],
    "answer": "Ancient India was largely indebted to Iranian ideas and practices."
  },
  {
    "number": 26,
    "question": "The meaning of the idiom \"to cook somebody's goose\" is:",
    "options": [
      "exaggerate the good qualities of a person",
      "ensure that somebody wins",
      "prepare a delicious dish",
      "ensure that somebody fails"
    ],
    "answer": "ensure that somebody fails"
  },
  {
    "number": 27,
    "question": "Choose the best antonym for OBLITERATE:",
    "options": [
      "exculpate",
      "forge",
      "abhorrent",
      "None of these"
    ],
    "answer": "forge"
  },
  {
    "number": 28,
    "question": "What do we call a group of dolphins?",
    "options": [
      "a herd",
      "a pride",
      "a pod",
      "a swarm"
    ],
    "answer": "a pod"
  },
  {
    "number": 29,
    "question": "What is the feminine gender of 'ram'?",
    "options": [
      "doe",
      "jenny",
      "mare",
      "ewe"
    ],
    "answer": "ewe"
  },
  {
    "number": 30,
    "question": "Choose the best synonym for DOCILE:",
    "options": [
      "gentle",
      "puzzling",
      "stupid",
      "stubborn"
    ],
    "answer": "gentle"
  },
  {
    "number": 31,
    "question": "An accounting system which presents the Balance sheet in two parts is called:",
    "options": [
      "Double entry",
      "Single entry",
      "Double accounting",
      "Statement of affairs"
    ],
    "answer": "Double accounting"
  },
  {
    "number": 32,
    "question": "Voyage Account is ___ account.",
    "options": [
      "Nominal",
      "Real",
      "Personal",
      "None of these"
    ],
    "answer": "Nominal"
  },
  {
    "number": 33,
    "question": "In self balancing Bought Ledger Adjustment Account is opened in:",
    "options": [
      "Bought Ledger",
      "General Ledger",
      "Sold Ledger",
      "None of these"
    ],
    "answer": "General Ledger"
  },
  {
    "number": 34,
    "question": "Manufacturing Account is prepared to find out:",
    "options": [
      "Cost of goods sold",
      "Cost of goods produced",
      "Net profit",
      "Work in progress"
    ],
    "answer": "Cost of goods produced"
  },
  {
    "number": 35,
    "question": "The amount paid to an author for the use of copyright is called:",
    "options": [
      "Minimum rent",
      "Commission",
      "Patent",
      "Royalty"
    ],
    "answer": "Royalty"
  },
  {
    "number": 36,
    "question": "___ refer to the amount spent on fuel, coal, diesel and freshwater used for the purpose of voyage.",
    "options": [
      "Port charges",
      "Bunker cost",
      "Primage",
      "Passage money"
    ],
    "answer": "Bunker cost"
  },
  {
    "number": 37,
    "question": "Where the loss of an asset has been identified by the bank, but the amount has not been written off wholly or partly is known as:",
    "options": [
      "Bad debts",
      "Sub standard assets",
      "Loss asset",
      "Doubtful assets"
    ],
    "answer": "Loss asset"
  },
  {
    "number": 38,
    "question": "Under inflationary condition ___ method will show highest value of closing stock.",
    "options": [
      "LIFO",
      "FIFO",
      "Average price",
      "None of these"
    ],
    "answer": "FIFO"
  },
  {
    "number": 39,
    "question": "Anil drew a bill on Binil for Rs. 30,000 for three months. Proceeds are to be shared equally. A got the bill discounted @ 12% per annum and remits the required proceeds to 'B'. The amount of such remittance will be:",
    "options": [
      "Rs. 15,000",
      "Rs. 14,500",
      "Rs. 14,550",
      "Rs. 14,650"
    ],
    "answer": "Rs. 14,550"
  },
  {
    "number": 40,
    "question": "During the year 2013 a business concern earned a net profit of Rs. 42,000. The manager is entitled to a commission of 5% of the net profit. Find the amount of the commission so charged.",
    "options": [
      "Rs. 2,000",
      "Rs. 2,100",
      "Rs. 2,200",
      "Rs. 2,010"
    ],
    "answer": "Rs. 2,100"
  },
  {
    "number": 41,
    "question": "Valuation and presentation of inventories is:",
    "options": [
      "IAS 5",
      "IAS 4",
      "IAS 1",
      "IAS 2"
    ],
    "answer": "IAS 2"
  },
  {
    "number": 42,
    "question": "Accounting principles are based on:",
    "options": [
      "Objectivity",
      "Convenience",
      "Practicability",
      "Subjectivity"
    ],
    "answer": "Objectivity"
  },
  {
    "number": 43,
    "question": "Find the odd one:",
    "options": [
      "Purchase Book",
      "Sales Book",
      "Purchase Return Book",
      "Cash Book"
    ],
    "answer": "Cash Book"
  },
  {
    "number": 44,
    "question": "A credit Sale of Rs. 5,000 to Sugunan has been wrongly passed through the purchase book. To rectify the error, Sugunan's Account is debited with:",
    "options": [
      "Rs. 10,000",
      "Rs. 5,000",
      "Rs. 15,000",
      "Rs. 20,000"
    ],
    "answer": "Rs. 10,000"
  },
  {
    "number": 45,
    "question": "What is the total earnings of a worker from the following data? Standard time for completing the job 50 hours. Actual time taken for completing the job 45 hours. Time rate is Rs. 20 per hour, premium bonus is 60% of time saved.",
    "options": [
      "Rs. 900",
      "Rs. 960",
      "Rs. 980",
      "Rs. 950"
    ],
    "answer": "Rs. 960"
  },
  {
    "number": 46,
    "question": "What is the Economic Order Quantity if annual requirement is 1,600 units, cost of material per unit is Rs. 40, cost of placing and receiving order Rs. 50. Annual carrying cost of inventory is 10% of inventory value?",
    "options": [
      "220 Units",
      "200 Units",
      "280 Units",
      "300 Units"
    ],
    "answer": "200 Units"
  },
  {
    "number": 47,
    "question": "If sales is Rs. 2,40,000; percent of gross profit on sales 20%, purchase Rs. 1,75,000, closing stock Rs. 30,000. Then opening stock will be:",
    "options": [
      "Rs. 47,000",
      "Rs. 60,000",
      "Rs. 50,000",
      "Rs. 67,000"
    ],
    "answer": "Rs. 47,000"
  },
  {
    "number": 48,
    "question": "Find the odd one out:",
    "options": [
      "Waste Book",
      "Day Book",
      "Rough Book",
      "Memorandum Book"
    ],
    "answer": "Memorandum Book"
  },
  {
    "number": 49,
    "question": "If cost of an asset is Rs. 60,000 and life period is 4 years. The rate of depreciation is:",
    "options": [
      "20%",
      "30%",
      "25%",
      "33%"
    ],
    "answer": "25%"
  },
  {
    "number": 50,
    "question": "When furniture is purchased for Rs. 10,000:",
    "options": [
      "Capital is decreased",
      "No change in capital",
      "Capital is increased",
      "Total amount of asset is changed"
    ],
    "answer": "No change in capital"
  },
  {
    "number": 51,
    "question": "___ ignores the outstanding income while preparing their income statement.",
    "options": ["Sole traders", "Contractors", "Doctors", "Single Entry traders"],
    "answer": "Single Entry traders"
  },
  {
    "number": 52,
    "question": "Identify the odd one:",
    "options": ["Preliminary Expenses", "Repairs and Maintenance", "Erection Expenses", "Establishment Expenses"],
    "answer": "Repairs and Maintenance"
  },
  {
    "number": 53,
    "question": "Before acceptance by the drawee a bill of exchange is known as:",
    "options": ["Contract", "Agreement", "Draft", "None of these"],
    "answer": "Draft"
  },
  {
    "number": 54,
    "question": "___ is against the principle of convention of conservatism.",
    "options": ["Provision for Bad-debts", "Provision for discount on debtors", "Provision for discount on creditors", "Provision for depreciation"],
    "answer": "Provision for discount on creditors"
  },
  {
    "number": 55,
    "question": "The term ___ is used to write off the value of lease hold properties.",
    "options": ["Amortization", "Depreciation", "Obsolescence", "Depletion"],
    "answer": "Amortization"
  },
  {
    "number": 56,
    "question": "If direct material consumed is Rs. 60,000, Direct Labour cost is Rs. 20,000, Factory overheads expense is Rs. 10,000, opening and closing work-in-progress are Rs. 15,000 and Rs. 18,000 respectively, then works cost will be:",
    "options": ["Rs. 80,000", "Rs. 87,000", "Rs. 1,05,000", "Rs. 90,000"],
    "answer": "Rs. 87,000"
  },
  {
    "number": 57,
    "question": "Ram sends 50 table fans to Rahim costing Rs. 300 per table fan, to be sold at 20% above cost price. Sales will be:",
    "options": ["Rs. 18,000", "Rs. 15,000", "Rs. 20,000", "Rs. 22,000"],
    "answer": "Rs. 18,000"
  },
  {
    "number": 58,
    "question": "If the cash book does not contain discount columns, discount allowed and received will be passed through:",
    "options": ["Discount Account", "Journal", "Day Book", "Suspense Account"],
    "answer": "Journal"
  },
  {
    "number": 59,
    "question": "___ is considered for the calculation of Capital Fund.",
    "options": ["Salary outstanding", "Subscription outstanding", "Subscription prepaid of last year", "Salary prepaid"],
    "answer": "Subscription outstanding"
  },
  {
    "number": 60,
    "question": "Find the odd one:",
    "options": ["Dock dues", "Octroi", "Carriage", "Export duty"],
    "answer": "Carriage"
  },
  {
    "number": 61,
    "question": "2, 5, 11, 17, 23, ___",
    "options": ["21", "31", "34", "29"],
    "answer": "29"
  },
  {
    "number": 62,
    "question": "0, 5, 22, 57, 116, ___",
    "options": ["205", "200", "161", "None of these"],
    "answer": "205"
  },
  {
    "number": 63,
    "question": "Which is the smallest number of six digits which is divisible by 111?",
    "options": ["100121", "111111", "100111", "100011"],
    "answer": "100011"
  },
  {
    "number": 64,
    "question": "What is 90% of 90% of 100?",
    "options": ["63", "72", "81", "90"],
    "answer": "81"
  },
  {
    "number": 65,
    "question": "333333 + 1.1 =",
    "options": ["3130", "303030", "3010", "31003"],
    "answer": "303030"
  },
  {
    "number": 66,
    "question": "From a given point, how many tangents can be drawn to a circle?",
    "options": ["0", "1", "2", "3"],
    "answer": "2"
  },
  {
    "number": 67,
    "question": "Ravi ranks 18th in a class of forty students. What is his rank from the last?",
    "options": ["23", "20", "19", "24"],
    "answer": "23"
  },
  {
    "number": 68,
    "question": "If the time in a clock is 9 hours 20 minutes, what time does it show on a mirror?",
    "options": ["2 hours 40 min.", "4 hours 20 min.", "6 hours 20 min.", "4 hours 40 min."],
    "answer": "2 hours 40 min."
  },
  {
    "number": 69,
    "question": "5^(25)^-1 + (5^-1(25)^-1) = ?",
    "options": ["0", "20", "25", "5"],
    "answer": "0"
  },
  {
    "number": 70,
    "question": "Find the angle between the minute hand and the hour hand of a clock when the time is 7.20?",
    "options": ["90°", "95°", "100°", "105°"],
    "answer": "100°"
  },
  {
    "number": 71,
    "question": "If the progression 3, 10, 17, ... and 63, 65, 67, ... are such that their nth terms are equal, then the value of n is?",
    "options": ["17", "13", "63", "20"],
    "answer": "13"
  },
  {
    "number": 72,
    "question": "How many three digit numbers are there in which all the digits are distinct?",
    "options": ["648", "548", "608", "508"],
    "answer": "648"
  },
  {
    "number": 73,
    "question": "A number when divided by 342 gives a remainder 47. When the same number is divided by 19, what should be the remainder?",
    "options": ["12", "13", "9", "7"],
    "answer": "9"
  },
  {
    "number": 74,
    "question": "The angles of a triangle are in the ratio of 4 : 6 : 10. What is the value of the largest angle?",
    "options": ["60°", "90°", "70°", "80°"],
    "answer": "90°"
  },
  {
    "number": 75,
    "question": "The sum of numerator and denominator of a certain fraction is 11. If one is added to the numerator, the value of fraction becomes 1/2. The fraction is:",
    "options": ["8/3", "4/7", "5/6", "None of these"],
    "answer": "5/6"
  },
  {
    "number": 76,
    "question": "The speed of a car is twice that of a truck. Both started from Palakkadu and reached at Salem. If the truck took 3 hours more than the car, what was the time taken by the truck to reach at Salem?",
    "options": ["9 hours", "6 hours", "5 hours", "4 hours"],
    "answer": "6 hours"
  },
  {
    "number": 77,
    "question": "A farmer has 50 kg wheat in hand, part of which he sells at 8% profit and the rest at 18% profit. He gains 14% altogether. What is the quantity of wheat sold by him at 18% profit?",
    "options": ["25 kg", "15 kg", "40 kg", "30 kg"],
    "answer": "30 kg"
  },
  {
    "number": 78,
    "question": "The sum of two numbers is 2490. If 6.5% of one number is equal to 8.5% of other, then one of the number is:",
    "options": ["1200", "1301", "1411", "2070"],
    "answer": "1411"
  },
  {
    "number": 79,
    "question": "Weight of a cow and a buffalo are in the ratio of 4 : 5. Cow's weight increases by 10% and the total weight of cow and buffalo together becomes 82.8 kg, with an increase of 15%. By what percent does the weight of the buffalo increase?",
    "options": ["20%", "19%", "27%", "29%"],
    "answer": "27%"
  },
  {
    "number": 80,
    "question": "The least number of square tiles required to pave the floor of a room having length 11 m 47 cm and 10 m 36 cm breadth is",
    "options": ["868", "930", "880", "836"],
    "answer": "930"
  },
  {
    "number": 81,
    "question": "If the radius of a cylinder is doubled and the height is halved, what is the ratio between the new volume and previous volume?",
    "options": ["1:2", "2:3", "2:1", "None of these"],
    "answer": "2:1"
  },
  {
    "number": 82,
    "question": "How many days will be there from January 1992 to April 1992?",
    "options": ["120", "121", "119", "122"],
    "answer": "121"
  },
  {
    "number": 83,
    "question": "Area of square field is one hectare. What is the length of the diagonal?",
    "options": ["100", "1002", "50", "50/2"],
    "answer": "141.42"
  },
  {
    "number": 84,
    "question": "A Chess board contains 64 equal squares and the area of each square is 2.56 cm². Find the length of one side of the chess board?",
    "options": ["12.8", "10.2", "13.4", "14.6"],
    "answer": "12.8"
  },
  {
    "number": 85,
    "question": "In how many ways can 5 persons be seated around a circular table in a meeting?",
    "options": ["22", "20", "24", "26"],
    "answer": "24"
  },
  {
    "number": 86,
    "question": "Father is 4 times as old as his son, in 30 years he will be only twice as old as his son. Then the present age of the father is",
    "options": ["50 years", "60 years", "80 years", "40 years"],
    "answer": "60 years"
  },
  {
    "number": 87,
    "question": "The length of a rectangle is increased by 20%. What will be the percentage decrease in its breadth so as to have the same area?",
    "options": ["16⅔%", "14¼%", "11⅖%", "10⅓%"],
    "answer": "16⅔%"
  },
  {
    "number": 88,
    "question": "The average of 11 results is 60. If the average of the first 6 result is 59 and that of the last six is 62, find the sixth result?",
    "options": ["66", "76", "56", "70"],
    "answer": "66"
  },
  {
    "number": 89,
    "question": "Six bells commence tolling together at regular intervals of 3, 6, 9, 12, 15 and 18 seconds respectively. In 30 minutes, how many times do they toll together?",
    "options": ["13", "17", "11", "19"],
    "answer": "11"
  },
  {
    "number": 90,
    "question": "The average of the two digit numbers which remains the same when the digits interchange their positions.",
    "options": ["45", "55", "65", "74"],
    "answer": "55"
  },
  {
    "number": 91,
    "question": "A school has only three classes comprised of 40, 50 and 60 students respectively. In these classes, 10%, 20% and 10% students respectively passed in the examinations. What is the percentage of students passed in the examination from the entire school?",
    "options": ["12⅓%", "15⅓%", "11⅓%", "13⅓%"],
    "answer": "12⅓%"
  },
  {
    "number": 92,
    "question": "The salary of a worker was first increased by 10% and thereafter decreased by 7%. What was the change in his salary?",
    "options": ["4.5%", "5.6%", "2.3%", "3.4%"],
    "answer": "2.3%"
  },
  {
    "number": 93,
    "question": "The sides of a triangle are in the ratio 2:3:4. If the perimeter is 117 cm, find the length of the smallest side?",
    "options": ["27", "28", "34", "38"],
    "answer": "26"
  },
  {
    "number": 94,
    "question": "Sasi and Soman agreed to do a work for Rs. 112. Sasi alone can do it in 7 days and Soman alone in 8 days. With the help of another man they can finish the work in 3 days, then what amount does the man get?",
    "options": ["30", "42", "32", "22"],
    "answer": "30"
  },
  {
    "number": 95,
    "question": "A car during its journey travels 30 minutes at the speed of 40 km/hr, another 45 minutes at the speed of 60 km/hr and for two hours at a speed of 70 km/hr. Find the average speed of the car?",
    "options": ["70 km/hr", "63 km/hr", "53 km/hr", "None of these"],
    "answer": "63 km/hr"
  },
  {
    "number": 96,
    "question": "Everybody in a room shake hands with one another. The total number of handshakes is 66. The number of persons in the room is",
    "options": ["12", "11", "14", "16"],
    "answer": "12"
  },
  {
    "number": 97,
    "question": "A mathematics paper consists of ten questions, which is divided into two parts, I and II, each part contains five questions each. A student is required to attempt six questions in all, taking at least two questions from each part. In how many ways can the student select the questions?",
    "options": ["100", "150", "200", "243"],
    "answer": "150"
  },
  {
    "number": 98,
    "question": "In an election, involving two candidates, 132 votes were declared as invalid. The winning candidate got 54% of the votes and won by 192 votes. The total number of votes polled was",
    "options": ["2400", "2532", "2530", "2525"],
    "answer": "2525"
  },
  {
    "number": 99,
    "question": "A vessel contains 10 litres of milk. First, 2 litres of the content are removed and replaced by 2 litres of water. Subsequently, 4 litres of vessel's contents is removed and replaced by 4 litres of water. Finally, 6 litres of vessel's contents is removed and replaced by 6 litres of water. What is the quantity of milk left in the vessel?",
    "options": ["1.92 litres", "1.82 litres", "1.72 litres", "1.62 litres"],
    "answer": "1.62 litres"
  },
  {
  "number": 100,
  "question": "In a club 70% members read English newspapers and 75% members read Malayalam newspapers, while 20% do not read both papers. If 325 members read both the newspapers, then the total number of members in the club is:",
  "options": ["600","400","450","500"],
  "answer": "500"
  }
                  ]}]
  },
  {
   "course":"Arithmetic",
   "questionpapers":[{}]
  },
  {
   "course":"Zoology Lecturer",
   "questionpapers":[]
  },
  {
   "course":"Assistant",
   "questionpapers":[]
  },
  {
   "course":"Auditor",
   "questionpapers":[]
  },
  {
   "course":"Ayurveda",
   "questionpapers":[]
  },
  {
   "course":"Book Keeping",
   "questionpapers":[]
  },
  {
   "course":"Carpenter",
   "questionpapers":[]
  },
  {
   "course":"Catering And Restaurant",
   "questionpapers":[]
  },
  {
   "course":"Chemical",
   "questionpapers":[]
  },
  {
   "course":"Chemistry Lecturer",
   "questionpapers":[]
  },
  {
   "course":"Civil",
   "questionpapers":[]
  },
  {
   "course":"Commerce Lecturer",
   "questionpapers":[]
  },
  {
   "course":"Computer",
   "questionpapers":[]
  },
  {
   "course":"Dairing",
   "questionpapers":[]
  },
  {
   "course":"Data Entry",
   "questionpapers":[]
  },
  {
   "course":"Development Officer",
   "questionpapers":[]
  },
  {
   "course":"Draftsman",
   "questionpapers":[]
  },
  {
   "course":"Drawing",
   "questionpapers":[]
  },
  {
   "course":"Economics Lecturer",
   "questionpapers":[]
  },
  {
   "course":"Electrical",
   "questionpapers":[]
  },
  {
   "course":"Electronics",
   "questionpapers":[]
  },
  {
   "course":"English Lecturer",
   "questionpapers":[]
  },
  {
   "course":"Excise",
   "questionpapers":[]
  },
  {
   "course":"Forest",
   "questionpapers":[]
  },
  {
   "course":"Front Office",
   "questionpapers":[]
  },
  {
   "course":"General Insurance",
   "questionpapers":[]
  },
  {
   "course":"General Manager",
   "questionpapers":[]
  },
  {
   "course":"Geography Lecturer",
   "questionpapers":[]
  },
  {
   "course":"Health",
   "questionpapers":[]
  },
  {
   "course":"History Lecturer",
   "questionpapers":[]
  },
  {
   "course":"Hospitality",
   "questionpapers":[]
  },
  {
   "course":"Islamic History",
   "questionpapers":[]
  },
  {
   "course":"Khadi Officer",
   "questionpapers":[]
  },
  {
   "course":"LD Clerk",
   "questionpapers":[]
  },
  {
   "course":"LD Typist",
   "questionpapers":[]
  },
  {
   "course":"Librarian",
   "questionpapers":[]
  },
  {
   "course":"Marine Surveyor",
   "questionpapers":[]
  },
  {
   "course":"Mathematics Lecturer",
   "questionpapers":[]
  },
  {
   "course":"Mechanic",
   "questionpapers":[]
  },
  {
   "course":"Music Lecturer",
   "questionpapers":[]
  },
  {
   "course":"Operator",
   "questionpapers":[]
  },
  {
   "course":"Overseer",
   "questionpapers":[]
  },
  {
   "course":"Painter",
   "questionpapers":[]
  },
  {
   "course":"Personnel Officer",
   "questionpapers":[]
  },
  {
   "course":"Pharma",
   "questionpapers":[]
  },
  {
   "course":"Philosophy Lecturer",
   "questionpapers":[]
  },
  {
   "course":"Physics Lecturer",
   "questionpapers":[]
  },
  {
   "course":"Police",
   "questionpapers":[]
  },
  {
   "course":"Political Science",
   "questionpapers":[]
  },
  {
   "course":"Psychology Lecturer",
   "questionpapers":[]
  },
  {
   "course":"Public Relations Officer",
   "questionpapers":[]
  },
  {
   "course":"Radio Grapher",
   "questionpapers":[]
  },
  {
   "course":"Recording Assistant",
   "questionpapers":[]
  },
  {
   "course":"Sanitary Fitter",
   "questionpapers":[]
  },
  {
   "course":"Sociology Lecturer",
   "questionpapers":[]
  },
  {
   "course":"Statistics Lecturer",
   "questionpapers":[]
  },
  {
   "course":"Stenographer",
   "questionpapers":[]
  },
  {
   "course":"Steward",
   "questionpapers":[]
  },
  {
   "course":"Superintendent",
   "questionpapers":[]
  },
  {
   "course":"Supervisor",
   "questionpapers":[]
  },
  {
   "course":"Technician Medical",
   "questionpapers":[]
  },
  {
   "course":"Telephone Operator",
   "questionpapers":[]
  },
  {
   "course":"Tool And Die",
   "questionpapers":[]
  },
  {
   "course":"Work Supervisor",
   "questionpapers":[]
  }
]